Guide to the Edgar Odell Lovett and Mary Ellen Hale Lovett Family papers, 1849-1979 MS 494
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
- Series VII: Addenda, 1892-1952, 218782
  - Memorabilia, 218839
    - Mary Lovett-Notebook/diary, 1916, 218981 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Diary of Mary Lovett (includes Paris), 1920-1924, 218980 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Mary Lovett-Notebook, 1922, 218979 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Mary Lovett-Diary and correspondence, 1924, 218978 (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Mary Lovett-Diary, 1924-1925, 218977 (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Mary Lovett-Art League, 1924-1928, 218976 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Mary Lovett-Domestic expenses, packing lists, 1925-1926, 218975 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Record of Alexander's illness at Methodist Hospital, 1926; Easter and Christmas, 1926, 218974 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Mary Lovett-Diary with correspondence, 1927, 218973 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Mary Lovett-Diary, 1927, 218972 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Mary Lovett-Diary, 1928, 218971 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Mary Lovett-Diary, 1929, 218970 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Mary Lovett-Diary, 1930, 218969 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Mary Lovett-Diary, 1931, 218968 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Mary Lovett-Diary, 1932, 218967 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Mary Lovett-Diary with articles, 1940, 218966 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Mary Lovett-Day Journal, 1941, 218965 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Mary Lovett-Notebook and letters, 1941, 218964 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Mary Lovett-Diary, 1947, 218963 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Notes on Astronomy, 218962 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Lovett-"Some notes on the geometry of a pair of dividers," 1894 (University of Virginia?), 218961 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Electricity and Magnetism; Notes on Kinchoff's Laws-Voltaic Cells, 218960 (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Routh's Analytical Statistics, volume 1, index, 218959 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - The Strophoid-Valdes, 218958 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - The Velocity of the Earth's Rotation, 218957 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Calculations, 7 pages, 218956 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Arcs and Osculating Space, 218955 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Definition of Analytical Function, 218954 (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - The Science of Cosmogony, 218953 (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - American Journal of Mathematics, notes 1890-1891, 218952 (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - Notes: The Geometry of Transformations, 218951 (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - Zorawski's Biegungsinsvariantin (Curvature Variations)-Leipzig, 1895?, 218950 (Box 81, Folder 13)
    - Loose pages, Leipzig math papers, 1895, 1896, 218949 (Box 81, Folder 14)
    - Notebook (in German) of E.O. Lovett, probably Leipzig, 1895, 1896, 218948 (Box 81, Folder 15)
    - "On the Periodic Solutions to the Problem of Three Bodies"-Lovett, Princeton (1897-1905), 218947 (Box 81, Folder 16)
    - Lovett: Sophus Lies Transformation Groups. A series of Elementary Expository Articles. (Princeton, 1897), 218946 (Box 81, Folder 17)
    - Lovett-"Contact Transformations of Developable Surfaces, Princeton, 1897-1905, 218945 (Box 81, Folder 18)
    - Singular Solutions of Pfaff and Monge Equations, Princeton, 1898, 218944 (Box 81, Folder 19)
    - Lovett, Papers on Differential Variants, circa 1898, 218943 (Box 81, Folder 20)
    - Application of Dupin's Theorem for M. Darboux, 1900, 218942 (Box 81, Folder 21)
    - Lovett: "A Theorem in Determinants," undated, 218941 (Box 81, Folder 22)
    - Math Paper: The Transformation of the Rights, class notes 1900, for M. Darboux, Princeton, 218940 (Box 81, Folder 23)
    - Lovett math papers, 1901, Princeton, 218939 (Box 81, Folder 24)
    - Loose Pages, 1 of 2, 218938 (Box 81, Folder 25)
    - Loose Pages, 2 of 2, 218937 (Box 81, Folder 26)
    - Notes on Geodesy, University of Virginia, summer, 1891, 218936 (Box 81, Folder 27)
    - Lovett-Astronomical calculations, Leipzig, 1895, 218935 (Box 81, Folder 28)
    - Geometry papers in French, 218934 (Box 81, Folder 29)
    - Notes on Lines of Multiple Curvatures, Princeton, 218933 (Box 81, Folder 30)
    - American Mathematical Society letter, article pages, March 1900, 218932 (Box 81, Folder 31)
    - Course notes, Princeton, 1897-1905, 218931 (Box 81, Folder 32)
    - Course notes, lecture notes, 218930 (Box 81, Folder 33)
    - Astronomy course notes, lecture notes, undated, 218929 (Box 81, Folder 34)
    - Lovett: Transformation, papers, notes, undated, 218928 (Box 81, Folder 35)
    - Geometry notes, 218927 (Box 81, Folder 36)
    - Packet: "War work papers and booklets-personal papers", 218926 (Box 81, Folder 37)
    - Packet: "Cards, Notes, and List of gifts in '32", 218925 (Box 81, Folder 38)
    - E.O. Lovett academic citation notecards, undated, 218924 (Box 81, Folder 39)
    - E.O. Lovett, Exposition Internationale, Paris 1937-Identity Card, 218923 (Box 81, Folder 40)
    - School Exercise Book, Mary Hale, circa 1892, 218922 (Box 81, Folder 41)
    - School Exercise Book, Mary Hale, 1892?, 218921 (Box 81, Folder 42)
    - Mary Hale, Commencement, 1892, 218920 (Box 81, Folder 43)
    - Postcards from trip around the world, 1908-1909, 218919 (Box 81, Folder 44)
    - Passport, Mrs. Mary Lovett, 1920-1922, 218918 (Box 81, Folder 45)
    - Mary Hale Lovett's list of trunks and boxes stored at Rice Hotel, 1928, 218917 (Box 81, Folder 46)
    - Mary Hale Lovett's family record book with genealogy, 1928-1945, 218916 (Box 81, Folder 47)
    - Mary Hale Lovett notebook; letter drafts and family history, 218915 (Box 81, Folder 48)
    - Mary Hale Lovett's list of Room 807, Plaza Hotel, 1942, 218914 (Box 81, Folder 49)
    - Mary Hale Lovett notebook, Fall 1949, "Special Notes", 218913 (Box 81, Folder 50)
    - Mary Hale Lovett address book, 1948-1950, 218912 (Box 81, Folder 51)
    - Mary Hale Lovett address book, notes, 1928-1948, 218911 (Box 81, Folder 52)
    - Mary Hale Lovett maternal genealogy documents, 218910 (Box 81, Folder 53)
    - Silk Stockings (Mary Hale Lovett?), 218909 (Box 81, Folder 54)
    - Some of Adelaide Lovett's first embroidery for Tante, 218908 (Box 81, Folder 55)
    - Notes and statements to be kept for Adelaide's diary, 218907 (Box 81, Folder 56)
    - Ellen Kennedy Lovett birthday book, 218906 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Drawings by Adelaide Lovett, 218905 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Passport, Adelaide Lovett, 218904 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Lovett children papers, 218903 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Notebook, Annie B. Hale, 1890s-1900s, 218902 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - H.S. Hale notebook, 1898, 218901 (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Scrapbook of Mrs. H.S. Hale, 1884-, 218900 (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Sketch for gravestone for Virginia Adelaide Hale, 218899 (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Genealogies, 218898 (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Hale family bibles, 218897 (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - Hale family bible [pages], 218896 (Box 82, Folder 11)
    - Eliza Bell bible pages, 218895 (Box 82, Folder 12)
    - Family history notes, 1910-1928, 218894 (Box 82, Folder 13)
    - Major H.S. Hale biography, 218893 (Box 82, Folder 14)
    - Major H.S. Hale 80th birthday, 218892 (Box 82, Folder 15)
    - Major H.S. Hale military service, 218891 (Box 82, Folder 16)
    - Albert S. Hale-school compositions, 218890 (Box 82, Folder 17)
    - Thursday Arts Review, 218889 (Box 82, Folder 18)
    - Thursday Art Review, 1924, 218888 (Box 82, Folder 19)
    - Thursday Art Review, 1929-1945, 218887 (Box 82, Folder 20)
    - Memorials, 218886 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Dress Pattern (?), 3 pc., 218885 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Handwritten/colored book of Spencer poetry and ribbon binding, 218884 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Paper Dolls (3 sets), 218883 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Christmas Poem by Graeme Baker, 218882 (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Transcript of "The Third Day", 218881 (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Anonymous writing, 218880 (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Provence tour itinerary, 9/19/21, 218879 (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - Programs/invitations, 1888-1950, 218878 (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Invitations, 218877 (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - France, 218876 (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - Hale/Lovett wedding announcements, 1897, 218875 (Box 83, Folder 12)
    - Biographical references, 218874 (Box 83, Folder 13)
    - School reports/cards, 218873 (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - Graduation announcement, Joseph Theodore Hale, 218872 (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - University of Virginia Ribbons, 218871 (Box 83, Folder 16)
    - Commencement address at Washington and Lee University, 1924, given by Dr. Lindsey Blayney, 218870 (Box 83, Folder 17)
    - Portrait, 218869 (Box 83, Folder 18)
    - Constitution and By-laws of Economic Club of Houston, 218868 (Box 83, Folder 19)
    - Contents of JP Morgan & Co. Letter of Credit; Leather Pouch, 218867 (Box 83, Folder 20)
    - Packet: children's drawings, correspondence, Princeton directory, 218866 (Box 83, Folder 21)
    - Holland-America Line passenger list, 1900, 218865 (Box 83, Folder 22)
    - Packet of invoices, cheque stubs, 218864 (Box 83, Folder 23)
    - Invoices, 218863 (Box 83, Folder 24)
    - Packet of invoices, 218862 (Box 83, Folder 25)
    - Invoices, 218861 (Box 83, Folder 26)
    - Postcards, 218860 (Box 83, Folder 27)
    - Colored blank greeting cards, pieces, 218859 (Box 83, Folder 28)
    - Packet of holiday cards, programs, a feather, 218858 (Box 83, Folder 29)
    - Sunday school card mementos, 218857 (Box 83, Folder 30)
    - Colored advertisement cards; folder 1 of 2, 218856 (Box 83, Folder 31)
    - Colored advertisement cards; folder 2 of 2, 218855 (Box 83, Folder 32)
    - Postcards, 218854 (Box 83, Folder 33)
    - Copy of letter addressed to Mrs. James A. Baker, President of the Settlement Assoc., 1913, 218853 (Box 83, Folder 34)
    - Rice administrative documents, 218852 (Box 83, Folder 35)
    - Rice Institute faculty position offer, E.O.L. to Poincare, 1912, 218851 (Box 83, Folder 36)
    - Rice colors, 218850 (Box 83, Folder 37)
    - Personal notes of Dr. Edgar Odell Lovett, 218849 (Box 83, Folder 38)
    - Fragments of Rice stories, 218848 (Box 83, Folder 39)
    - Alliance Francais, 218847 (Box 83, Folder 40)
    - General fragments and unidentified items, 218846 (Box 83, Folder 41)
    - Notes describing Civil War in MS, 1864, by unknown writer, 218845 (Box 83, Folder 42)
    - Edgar Odell Lovett diploma: Doctor of Sciences from Colorado College, 218844 (Box 84, Folder -)
    - Panoramic photo: Christian Missionary Convention, Mayfield, KY, Sept. 24-27, 1923, 218843 (Box 84, Folder -)
    - Box of calling cards-friends, business acquaintances, family, 218842 (Box 84, Folder -)
    - Box of small books, notebooks, silver case, 218841 (Box 84, Folder -)
    - 3 boxes of commemorative medals and medallions, 218840 (Box 84, Folder -)
  - Publications, 218798
    - Academic-related, 218838 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Arts-related, 218837 (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Arts brochures and catalogs, 1940s, 218836 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Astronomy book catalog, n.d., 218835 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Astronomy bulletins, programs, 1874, 218834 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Certificates, 218833 (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Confederate monument certificate, 218832 (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Confederate publications, 218831 (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Exhibitions, 218830 (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - Garden party 1928, 218829 (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - Houston businesses, 218828 (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - Houston Democratic National Convention 1928, 218827 (Box 85, Folder 12)
    - Kentucky, State of, publications, 1876-1909, 218826 (Box 85, Folder 13)
    - Kentucky social invitations, 1893-1908, 218825 (Box 85, Folder 14)
    - Loomis Sanatorium (NY), 218824 (Box 85, Folder 15)
    - Lovett, Mrs. E.O. diagnosis 1906, 218823 (Box 85, Folder 16)
    - Mathematic problems conference address, 218822 (Box 85, Folder 17)
    - Mathematics bulletins 1879-1903, 218821 (Box 85, Folder 18)
    - Mathematics programs, announcements 1893-1900, 218820 (Box 85, Folder 19)
    - Musical-related, 218819 (Box 85, Folder 20)
    - News clips – Hale family, 218818 (Box 85, Folder 21)
    - News clips – Hale family, 218817 (Box 85, Folder 22)
    - News clips – Lovett & Rice, 218816 (Box 85, Folder 23)
    - News clips – general; folder 1 of 3, 218815 (Box 85, Folder 24)
    - News clips – general; folder 2 of 3, 218814 (Box 85, Folder 25)
    - News clips – general; folder 3 of 3, 218813 (Box 85, Folder 26)
    - Oxford University math & physics exam 1870, 218812 (Box 85, Folder 27)
    - Princeton University – general, 218811 (Box 85, Folder 28)
    - Princeton University social programs 1907-08, 218810 (Box 85, Folder 29)
    - Programs and invitations-general, 218809 (Box 85, Folder 30)
    - Religious-related, 218808 (Box 85, Folder 31)
    - School commencement programs 1900-1908, 218807 (Box 85, Folder 32)
    - Societies, 218806 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Solicitations and advertisements 1940s, 218805 (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Star Refining & Producing Co., 218804 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Stationery examples, 218803 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Travel-related, 218802 (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - US Customs and passport information 1937, 218801 (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - "War Work papers"; folder 1 of 2, 218800 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - "War Work papers"; folder 2 of 2, 218799 (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Offprints and articles, 218783
    - "The Cabots Speak to the People", 218797 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - "Climate and Vegetation of Brazil", 218796 (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - "Constitution of Nature", 218795 (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - "A Great State Comes of Age", 218794 (Box 86, Folder 12)
    - "Houston's Greatest Civic Need", 218793 (Box 86, Folder 13)
    - "The Late R.H. Gardiner of Mayfield, KY", 218792 (Box 86, Folder 14)
    - "Mathematical Miscellany", 218791 (Box 86, Folder 15)
    - "Mathematical Repository", 218790 (Box 86, Folder 16)
    - "Note on Geometry of Four Dimensions", 218789 (Box 86, Folder 17)
    - Scientific Monthly, Sept. 1926, 218788 (Box 86, Folder 18)
    - "Sulla Classificazione delle Superficie di Kummer", 218787 (Box 86, Folder 19)
    - "Unique in the Republic", 218786 (Box 86, Folder 20)
    - "What Congress Can Do for the Cotton Farmer", 218785 (Box 86, Folder 21)
    - "What Price Cotton?", 218784 (Box 86, Folder 22)
- Series VIII: Alex Lovett letters, 1926-1928, 218747
  - Correspondence: 1926, 218777
    - Envelope Addressed to Mr. Edgar Odell Lovett from The Hill School, 218781 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - To Edgar Lovett from The Hill School, 1926, 218780 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Report Cards for L. Alexander Lovett from The Hill School, 218779 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Handwritten Notes, 218778 (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: 1927, 218755
    - To Mrs. Lovett from Alex Lovett, April 1927, 218776 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Mrs. Lovett from Alex Lovett, April 1927, 218775 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Mrs. Lovett from Alex Lovett with School Work and Concert Programs, April 1927, 218774 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Alex Lovett from Mrs. Lovett with newspaper clippings, April 1927, 218773 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Dr. and Mrs. Lovett from Alex Lovett, April-May 1927, 218772 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Mrs. Lovett with Hill School Dramatic Club Program, May 1924, 218771 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Mrs. Lovett from Alex Lovett, May 1927, 218770 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Mrs. Lovett from Alex Lovett, September 1927, 218769 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Alex Lovett, October 1927, 218768 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Alex Lovett, October 1927, 218767 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Dr. and Mrs. Lovett with Report Cards, October 1927, 218766 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Mrs. Lovett from Alex Lovett, October 1927, 218765 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Alex Lovett, November 1927, 218764 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Dr. Lovett from The Hill School, October-December 1927, 218763 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Alex Lovett, November 1927, 218762 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Alex Lovett from Mrs. Lovett, November 1927, 218761 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Mrs. Lovett from Alex Lovett, November 1927, 218760 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Mrs. Lovett from Alex Lovett, November 1927, 218759 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Mrs. Lovett from Alex Lovett, November 1927, 218758 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Mrs. Lovett from Alex Lovett, December 1927, 218757 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - To Mrs. Lovett from Alex Lovett, December 1927, 218756 (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1928, 218748
    - To Mrs. Lovett from Alex Lovett, November 1927-January 1928, 218754 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - To Mrs. Lovett from Alex Lovett, January 1928, 218753 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - To Mrs. Lovett from Alex Lovett, January 1928, 218752 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - To Mrs. Lovett from Alex Lovett, February 1928, 218751 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - To Mrs. Lovett from Alex Lovett, March-May 1928, 218750 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - To Mrs. Lovett from Alex Lovett, November 1928, 218749 (Box 87, Folder 3)